

💌 contact@krawczuk.eu | 🌴 https://krawczuk.eu | 🖸 igor-krawczuk | 🛅 igorkrawczuk | 🞓 Igor Krawczuk

"Learning is Living"

## **Summary** \_

Originally trained as an electrical and computer engineer, I am currently a researcher and terminal Ph.D. student at the LIONS laboratory at EPFL. My doctoral studies started with neuromorphic computing hardware - trying to build brain inspired ML accelerators - and slowly drifted into applied ML and ML/optimization theory. This has given me the chance to work with the "full stack" of ML research and engineering, going from hardware design, over systems programming with C,C++ and Rust, to large scale ML and RL systems in tensorflow, pytorch and jax. I also supervised over 20 students and interns, worked with half a doze industrial partners, co-founded 3 startups and ran the IT infrastructure in our lab.

I am interested in using the language of ML and optimization theory to improve products, automate and analyze decision making and design better institutions and autonomous systems.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### LSM and LIONS labs @ EPFL

Lausane, Switzerland

Sep. 2017 - Sep 2023 (est)

RESEARCHER & Ph.D CANDIDATE

- 6 conference publications, worked with over a dozen industry partners
- supervised 24 students in semester, Bachelors and Master students, as well as 2 interns
- participated in grant writing that brought 200'000 CHF of funding to the lab
- lab side sysadmin for a cluster of 30 machines, contact person for procurement of over 250'000 CHF
- Deployed a centralized monitoring environment(Grafana, InfluxDB) to quantify the usage of this cluster

Samsung Korea Seoul, S.Korea

VISITING RESEARCHER Apr. 2018 - Jun. 2018

- · As part of my PhD I had the chance to work on high dimensional multi-objective optimisations using Gaussian Processes in conjunction with evolutionary algorithms
- · Gathered requirements from my hosting division, surveyed the literature for fitting solutions, prepared and validated a PoC and faciliated knowledge transfer to the team for full implementation

SCI-STI-MM@EPFL Lausanne, Switzerland

RESEARCH INTERN

Mar. 2017 - Aug. 2017

- Researching the possibilities of Machine Learning in Dataflow Programming
- Developed a decision tree based scheduler for dataflow programs

ML/AI freelancer EU area

Aug. 2014 - Feb 2017 ML/AI PROTOTYPING CONSULTANCY

- Freelance consultant, designed and implemented a range of projects from Embedded System Firmware(C) over custom crawler, ETL and classification stacks(Python) to automated lead tracking using NLP (Python) and more
- Highlight 1: Developed a custom C++ and RocM based ML framework for a client with AMD GPUs before they were supported by Tensorflow etc.
- Highlight 2: Prototyped computer vision algorithms for aquaculture heatlh monitoring

**Blik** Munich, Germany

RESIDENT CONSULTANT/TECH LEAD Developing the first product iteration of their integrated intra-logistics Localization and tracking system

**EPFL** 

Lausanne, Switzerland

TA & LABORATORY ASSISTANT · Characterized Metal-Oxide Memristors using Agilent ATP

• Guided and supported students through VHDL implementations of Multi-Core CPUs

Nov 2015 - May 2015

Nov. 2016- Feb. 2017

#### **Publications**

Note: The \* indicates equal contribution

\*Fabian Latorre, \*Igor Krawczuk, \*Leello Tadesse Dadi, Thomas Pethick, Volkan Cevher ADVERSARIAL TRAINING DESCENDS WITHOUT DESCENT: FINDING ACTUAL DESCENT DIRECTIONS BASED ON DANSKIN'S THEOREM Accepted to ICLR 2023

#### Distributed Extra-gradient with Optimal Complexity and Communication Guarantees

\*ALI RAMEZANI-KEBRYA. \*KIMON ANTONAKOPOULOS. \*IGOR KRAWCZUK. \*JUSTIN DESCHENAUX. VOLKAN CEVHER

Accepted to ICLR 2023

#### DiGress: Discrete Denoising diffusion for graph generation

\*CLEMENT VIGNAC, \*IGOR KRAWCZUK, ANTOINE SIRAUDIN, BOHAN WANG, VOLKAN CEVHER, PASCAL FROSSARD

Accepted to ICLR 2023

#### **Proximal Point Imitation Learning**

Luca Viano, Angeliki Kamoutsi, Gergely Neu, Igor Krawczuk, Volkan Cevher

NeurIPS 2022

# A Computational Turn in Policy Process Studies: Coevolving Network Dynamics of Policy

Change

Maxime Stauffer, Isaak Mengesha, Konrad Seifert, **Igor Krawczuk**, Jens Fischer, Giovanna Di Marzo Serugendo

Complexity

2022-04-13

# Filling gaps in trustworthy development of AI

Shahar Avin, Haydn Belfield, Miles Brundage, Gretchen Krueger, Jasmine Wang, Adrian Weller, Markus Anderljung, **Igor Krawczuk**, David Krueger, Jonathan Lebensold, Tegan Maharaj, Noa Zilberman

Science 2021-21-09

#### Toward Trustworthy AI Development: Mechanisms for Supporting Verifiable Claims

MILES BRUNDAGE, SHAHAR AVIN, JASMINE WANG, HAYDN BELFIELD, GRETCHEN KRUEGER, GILLIAN HADFIELD, HEIDY KHLAAF, JINGYING YANG, HELEN TONER, RUTH FONG, TEGAN MAHARAJ, PANG KOH, WEI, SARA HOOKER, JADE LEUNG, ANDREW TRASK, EMMA BLUEMKE, JONATHAN LEBENSOLD, CULLEN O'KEEFE, MARK KOREN, THÉO RYFFEL, JB RUBINOVITZ, TAMAY BESIROGLU, FEDERICA CARUGATI, JACK CLARK, PETER ECKERSLEY, SARAH HAAS, DE, MARITZA JOHNSON, BEN LAURIE, ALEX INGERMAN,

2020-01-15

IGOR KRAWCZUK AND 29 OTHERS

Technical report, 183 citations on 2023-01-22

#### Multi-ReRAM synapses for artificial neural network training

Irem Boybat, Cecilia Giovinazzo, Elmira Shahrabi, **Igor Krawczuk**, Iason Giannopoulos, Christophe Piveteau, Manuel Le Gallo, Carlo Ricciardi, Abu Sebastian, Evangelos Eleftheriou, Yusuf Leblebici

2019 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)

https://arxiv.org/abs/2004.07213

2019-5-26

#### Effect of metal buffer layer and thermal annealing on HfOx-based ReRAMs

 ${\tt Jury\,Sandrini}, {\tt Behnoush\,Attarimashalkoubeh}, {\tt Elmira\,Shahrabi}, {\tt IGOR\,Krawczuk}, {\tt Yusuf\,Leblebici}$ 

2019 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS)

2016-11-16

### Education

#### EPFL (École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne)

Ph. D. candidate in Electrical Engineering

- Part of the "Data Champion" project whose members offer their technical expertise other EPFL members
- Completed the "PRINCE2 Foundation 6th Edition" project management certificate as part of the doctorate

#### **TUM (Technical University of Munich)**

M.Sc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

- Master thesis at EPFL as part of an ERASMUS exchange Aug. 2015 Nov. 2016
- Student representative on the faculty council, IT responsible for the student union

#### **TUM (Technical University of Munich)**

B.Sc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

• Member of the student union, treasurer responsible for over 250'000 € yearly cashflow

# Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2023 (est)

Lausanne, Switzerland

Munich, Germany

## Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2017

#### Munich, Germany

Sep. 2011 - Aug. 2014

#### **Honors & Awards**

2014

2015 **Deutschlandstipendium**, a German federal scholarship for excellent students

2015 **Semi-Finalist (with BioCloud**, OneStart Europe by Oxbridge Biotech and SR One

Impact Hub Zürich, Climate Kic & Pro Juventute Social Impact Award, HackZurich 2014

London, UK Zurich, Switzerland

# **Community service**

2018-2022 Reviewer for ICLR.

2019-2022 Reviewer for ICML,

2019-2022 Reviewer for NeuRIPS,

2019-2022 Reviewer for TMLR, Reviewed 2 papers

2020-2021 Mentor, CHERI existential risk summer program

Switzerland

JANUARY 22, 2023 IGOR KRAWCZUK · RÉSUMÉ